SAM (SAMANTHA) FREIS

freis.sam@gmail.com
Denver, CO
214-240-3558
www.sfreis.com
linkedin.com/in/sfreis/

SUMMARY

5+ years of experience in coordinating, designing, executing, and analyzing complex research projects focused on human behavior, cognition, and mental health. Proven ability to effectively communicate research findings and drive evidence-based decision-making. Collaborative team player advancing understanding of human behavior through research.

EXPERIENCE

04/2023 - present

DENVER MUSEUM OF NATURE AND SCIENCE

Research Assistant | On-site

 Advanced the priorities of the Community Research and Evaluation Team by collecting visitor feedback and <u>200+ surveys</u>

05/2022 - present

PROJECT SHORT

Co-Director of Evaluation and Development | Remote

- Utilized Qualtrics surveys and R to gather, triangulate, analyze, and visualize qualitative/quantitative feedback from 1,000+ participants
- Delivered actionable insights to the executive board, leading to improved support for international students, enhanced mentor recruitment, and expanded programming

08/2019 - present

UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO BOULDER

Researcher & Laboratory Instructor | On-site

- Produced <u>10 first-author scientific publications and conference presentations</u> using quantitative methods, including descriptive, inferential, and multivariate statistical analysis, exploratory data analysis, model evaluation and interpretation, structural equation modeling, and data visualization
- Collaborated on projects with cross-functional research teams and stakeholders across <u>5+ departments</u>, resulting in <u>15 co-author publications and presentations</u>
- Awarded a predoctoral training grant fellowship of \$150,000+ in tuition and stipend funding and a \$2,000 award for excellence in research
- Delivered engaging instruction in behavioral science, research methods, experimental design, AB tests, the R programming language, and statistics to <u>60 students, achieving</u> a 95% combined satisfaction rate

05/2017 - 06/2019

POPULATION RESEARCH CENTER, THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN Research Coordinator & Project Manager | On-site

- Enhanced lab efficiency and data quality by creating a research coordinator manual, automating tasks with reproducible code, <u>managing 10+ databases in REDcap</u>, and implementing data quality control measures
- Facilitated the expansion of a longitudinal cohort study with 1,000+ participants by harmonizing multiple diverse databases and research protocols
- Trained and led a team of <u>20+ research assistants</u> each semester in ethical research practices, data collection, psychometric testing, data entry, and participant recruitment and scheduling

EDUCATION

University of Colorado Boulder Ph.D., Psychology University of Colorado Boulder M.A., Psychology

The University of Texas at Austin B.S., Psychology, Biology Minor

SKILLS

- R, SQL, Mplus, SPSS, MS Office, GitHub
- Scientific writing and communication, leadership, teamwork, public speaking, grant writing, web copywriting